Professional Profile

Mark is an accomplished IT professional, with over 20 years extensive software development experience. He has been involved in multiple high profile software development projects across various industries and his career has taken him from code-cutting, then towards technical leadership and finally engineering leadership within an ASX listed SAAS company staffing 80-90 engineers..

He possesses strong skills in the field of software engineering with direct experience across the full software development lifecycle. He is a firm believer of agile processes and methodologies, and the importance of working with, attracting and retaining the best technologists in the industry. He has a keen interest in technology, the application of design patterns within software and usage of industry standard best practices. He is passionate about software development and is an active spectator in an industry where competing methodologies, tools and approaches keeps practitioners on their toes. He continually strives for those perfect projects, where great culture, great technology and great people come together to build something that makes a big difference.

The majority of his software development experience has been in Microsoft .Net technologies and he has an accomplished technical record on Windows .net technology stack, applied in an enterprise grade, multi-million dollar development context. He holds formal qualifications with a degree in Software Engineering where he graduated with first class honours. His technical skills are further enhanced with an added Business (majoring in finance with distinction) degree, placing extensive emphasis on pragmatic but well-engineered business-oriented solutions resulting in strong commercial outcomes.

Work History

Elmo Software: (Sep 2019 – current) Head of Engineering

- Oversee strategic and operational initiatives for ELMO's R&D Engineering team, consisting of 80 90 onshore and offshore engineers distributed across 12+ scrum teams.
- Reporting directly into CTO, 2IC in operational contingencies
- Accountable for rapid but sustainable, technical delivery of outcomes alongside contemporary engineering processes and practices.
- Full oversight of Engineering Budget
- Direct reports: 2 x Architects & 5 x Engineering Managers

Main achievements:

- Organisational redesign from project based teams towards multiple product aligned scrum teams
- Led architecture team towards envisioning and realisation of hybrid microservices architecture operating on AWS K8s environment
- Incepted and transitioned a new development hub in the Philippines (30 engineers and growing)
- Led quality culture, reducing number of incidents, defect escape rates, meet SLAs and SLOs, drastically improving DORA metrics.
- Streamlining operational processes in terms of recruitment, career progression and performance appraisal / review / compensation processes.
- Improved staff engagement through multiple initiatives, focus/quiet time, 10-20% time, hackathons, introduction of AI into the developer experience.

nib Travel: (June 2016 - Sep 2019)

2IC Head of Technology / Head of Software Development and Applications

- nib acquired WorldNomads Group, expanded responsibilities to Software Development and Delivery aspects of the IT department. Program management oversight across 4 development teams and application support team, consisting of 28-30 Permanent Headcount and pool of contractors (5-10). Motivate teams and create a strong culture of engineering excellence and continuous improvement.
- Act as 2IC Head of technology for short or extended periods during Head of Tech absences. Oversee day to day operations of 40-50 headcount. Oversaw Head of Tech role for 5 months in 2018.
- Responsible for the development and execution of 3-5 year cloud-first strategic direction, reporting to the Head of Tech, nib travel CEO and nib group CIO.
- Work with larger nib group it to realise efficiencies in group IT and develop and enhance group capabilities as required.
- Thought leadership and operational execution of business global expansion plan as well as technological uplifts and migration of local acquisitions (\$25m acquisition of QBE insurance with initial \$5m in tech acquisition costs)
- Development and expansion of group offshore development capabilities with a new software
 development team operating out of Philippines.
 Provide software development process leadership across all development teams within the IT
 department. Working directly with the Head of IT to be responsible for daily operations as well as the
 tactical and strategic direction of the IT department. Provide technical and process leadership role,
 mentoring and coaching teams, leaders and individuals towards successful delivery.
- Full oversight of strategic and operational spend of \$12m-13m (opex and capex) yearly technology departmental budget.
- Responsible for building and enhancing the company's overall technical delivery capability through selective recruitment and in-house training.

Main Achievements

- Organisational redesign scaling technical and engineering teams towards customer-centric purpose led capability driven models. Setting the foundations for our next stage of growth.
- Oversee technical components and successful integration of large strategic acquisitions
- Defined the IT strategic vision for the 3-5 year horizon. Gained executive approval towards a 'Cloud-First' strategy and re-architecture of our current platform to be geared for global scale and expansion.
- Improved staff engagement through the adoption of a 'people first' mindset, growing and coaching leaders at all levels. Introduced the IT Department's Mission, Purpose Manifesto and Behaviors.
- Improvement of the overall organization wide Quarterly Planning Process

World Nomads Group: (April 2014 – June 2016)

Software Development Manager

- Reporting directly to executive management (Head of Technology and CEO) to deliver the program of work, effectively plan out the delivery program, manage expectations and meet critical business objectives.
- Enforcing agile development best-practices: Continuous Delivery, Continuous Integration, Continuous Improvement, cultivating product backlogs and technical backlogs, addressing technical debt.
- Training and mentoring developers from recruitment, new start through to build support. Conducting architectural, design and code reviews.
- Maintains a continued hands on approach. Key role is to work with the development teams and chief
 architect to validate and approve designs ensuring they fall in-line with our overall enterprise
 architecture.
- Leads the department's charge into Dev-Ops and Cloud-First strategy. Setting up our dev-ops practices. Evaluating and adopting Puppet as our Configuration Management System.
- Responsible for building and enhancing the company's overall technical delivery capability through selective recruitment and in-house training.

Main Achievements

- Continued adoption of agile methodologies across the organization.
- Introduction of MAN time all IT department staff are encouraged to devote 10% to 20% of their time towards projects that they are passionate about. This has been a major factor in the department's low staff turnover.

World Nomads Group: (April 2010 – April 2014)

Team Lead Software Developer

- Main role to providing both technical and software development process leadership across 2 teams within the IT department. Teams ranged in size from 5-8.
- Responsible for teams delivering high quality code (within sprints) and setting the standard for development teams to follow. Assessing new technologies and providing technical leadership when necessary. Key role is to work with the technical architect to validate and approve design decisions related to the .Net Solutions technical architecture
- Responsible for shifting the department from previous waterfall and at times ad-hoc methodologies towards best-practice truly Agile and XP methodologies. Emphasis on continuous delivery and a "get to prod" mentality shift. Responsible for introducing and implementing the agile-revolution within the company and turning the IT department to be a best-practice software house:
 - Emphasis on a truly agile working environment
 - Automated deployment and testing, code review processes, quality control and standards.
 - True Continuous integration and Continuous Delivery practices We pride ourselves in "getting to prod" every 2 weeks – without fail.
 - Introduction of work effort tracking, agile estimation, team retrospectives, product reviews and numerous other agile methodologies to a previously ad-hoc and reactive organization.
- Key technologies involved: .Net 4.0, C# ASP .net MVC 3.5, ASP .net, Entity Framework, Angular JS, Selenium, Sass, NUnit, Unity 2.0, TFS 2013, Jira, Confluence, Sql Server 2014 Database, Reporting Services, Analysis Services, Octopus Deploy, RabbitMq, M-Files, Puppet Enterprise

Main Achievements

Over a 4 year period - delivered the company's Core Insurance Platform. A platform with user-centric
consumer web and mobile applications that are high performing, scalable, maintainable and
integrates seamlessly with backend financial systems.

Lend Lease Ltd: (January 2008 – March 2010) Lead Software Developer

- Lead .net developer role across several software development projects for LendLease Global Information Systems. Delivering applications focused on management reporting and business intelligence.
- Developed best-practice and introduced to the development team standard approaches and tools to support and enhance the LendLease Software development life cycle. Usage of issue-tracking system, version control, automated deployment and testing, code review processes, quality control and standards. Introduced TFS 2008, continuous integration practices, work effort tracking and other agile methodologies to a very waterfall oriented organisation.
- Identified by management as a 'change agent'. Nominated to work with the management team on creating and rolling out process improvement initiatives aimed at reducing project rework and increasing the predictability of application development projects at LendLease.
- Serve as the technical and process gate for all.net based projects transitioning over from project build to production release. Ensure proper design, common standards and processes are applied during the project build and enforce an effective handover process to production support.
- Developed .net foundation framework for use across all .net projects within the organization.
- Responsible for design decisions related to .Net implementation and integration with external systems.
- Key technologies involved: C#, ASP .net 3.5, Linq-Sql, Javascript, NUnit, Subversion, TFS 2008, Jira Cruise Control, Web Client Software Factory, Telerik asp.net, AgilePoint BPMS Workflow, Sql Server 2005 Database, Reporting Services, Analysis Services, Performance Point, Kerberos, Java

Oakton Ltd: Consultant .Net Application Developer (March 2005 – January 2008)

Vero Insurance (January 2007 – January 2008)

Team Lead / Senior Software Developer (Asp.Net 2.0 project)

- Senior software developer involved in large 26 man project to deliver an online application for a large Insurance Company.
- Service Oriented Software Architecture
- Responsible for the development of system components in a web environment, as well as mentoring and reviewing software artifacts produced by team members.
- Undertake and contribute to heavy software processes to ensure the delivery of high quality software, on time and on budget.

Aristocrat Leisure Industries (June 2005 – January 2007) Senior Software Developer / Team Lead (WinForms project)

- Senior software developer involved in large scale software development effort with short time to market expectation. Large team environment (20+)
- Acted as team lead during the software implementation and stabilisation phase. Personally oversaw
 the installation and commissioning of the system in several major casinos outside Australia.
- Responsible for the delivery of key and major components from start to finish. From requirements
 gathering and analysis, design, implementation and product commissioning.

NSW Health (March 2005 – June 2005) Software Developer (Asp.Net 1.1 project).

University of Technology Sydney

Perl Developer & Linux System Administration Contract (June 2004 – March 2005)

Formal Qualifications

University of Technology Sydney

- Bachelor of Engineering in Software Engineering with 1st Class Honours
- Bachelor of Business majoring in Finance with Distinction
- Diploma in Engineering Practice

High School Education

- Girraween Selective High School UAI Achieved: 99.45
- School Dux Patrician Brothers High School Blacktown

Technical Certifications

RHCT- Red Hat Linux Certified Engineer

Contact Details

Email: m.dasco@gmail.com Mobile: 0414 930 826

References

Furnished upon request